Julien Deray Msc

Scala Programming **②** Team Leadership **②** Process Improvement Email: julien@deray.fr **●** Website: http://julien.deray.fr

Professional Profile

Scala Developer with 5 years' experience with Scala in fintech firms combined with consistent success in exceeding requirements to challenging timescales, motivating teams and driving lean, agile processes. A skilled communicator adept at collaborating and strategizing on business-critical, complex projects; skilful in managing key stakeholder relationships. Fluent in Scala as well as other languages with an expert grounding in database administration, information system analysis and functional programming.

Key Skills

Product Development A&D Strategic Planning FinTech & Blockchain Technology Agile Team Leadership, Motivation & Coaching Stakeholder Management Information System Analysis & Design Tool Development Scala Functional Programming Reactive Architecture Project Management Problem Solving Conflict Resolution Business Scaling Lean Processes Distributed Systems

Qualifications

- Certified Kanban Foundation KMP 1
- Certified Scrum Master | Scrum Alliance (2018)
- Masters: Computer Science | IMT Atlantique, Nantes / France Engineering School (2012 2015)
- Diploma: Computer Science (HND Equivalent) | University Institute of Computer Science, La Rochelle / France (2010 – 2012)

Career History

Oct 2017 – May 2020 Artos Systems Ltd, London

Artos Systems is an enterprise-grade, fast-growing SaaS company with teams of forward-thinking professionals at the forefront of technological developments. With 40 staff it aims to solve real-world problems by translating cross-organisational operational processes into the blockchain realm.

Jan 2020 – May 2020 Engineering Manager

Part of the management team reporting to CTO, solely responsible for leading and developing a solutions team of four set up to manage significant growth and provide fast prototyping / proof of concept proposals for clients. Variable stack: Play! Framework Scala; Node.js; React; Typescript.

- End to end project management from requirement gathering and analysis through architecture to CI/
 CD, production and client relationship management
- Worked directly with clients to establish requirements and update on progress
- Controlled project timelines and expenditures
- Created structure, procedures, tools, guidelines and handbooks, significantly increasing efficiencies
- Applied critical organisational, analysis and problem solving skills to programs
- Developed, coached and motivated the team to deliver fast to challenging deadlines

Oct 2017 – Jan 2020 Senior Back-End Engineer & Scrum Master

Initially the start-up's only engineer, accountable for the planning, execution and success of all back—end Ethereum Blockchain development projects as well as training up and supervising a growing agile software development team of six. Infrastructure as code with Terraform; cluster management with AWS's ECS.

- Built a scalable solution to reach high volumes on the Ethereum Blockchain
- Led development of highly scalable APIs written in Scala, using Akka HTTP
- Worked with Jenkins to build CI/CD pipeline
- Provided coaching and continuous improvement to the team

Jun 2016 – Oct 2017 CTO & Co-Founder | Mobillity / Mespo, London

Co-founder of this fintech with chatbot application built and developed internally - Stack: Play! 2 / Scala / Akka; React; MongoDB; Kubernetes / Docker; ELK stack; Jenkins; Google Cloud Platform.

- Conducted analytical, environmental, operational and performance studies to develop designs
- Prepared reports with innovative proposals to address both technical and process issues
- Startup BootCamp FinTech London cohort 2017
- Raised £100K angel round with £1.8M company valuation
- Recruited, managed and coached seven staff (five interns and two employees)
- Achieved a waiting list for the product of 800 customers and secured 100+ prior to 2018

Oct 2015 – Jun 2016 Full-stack Software Engineer | PDX Technology, London

Worked as the only developer in this start-up fintech platform providing Ethereum-powered P2P lending, reporting to the two founders. Accountable for the implementation of engineering technical practices, industry codes & standards and managed handling all IT tasks: front-end and back-end development and DevOps.

- Developed four fintech web applications using Play! / Scala and AngularJS / React.js with MongoDB, deployed on Heroku and EC2
- Drew many dynamic financial charts using C3.js / D3.js and WebSockets
- Coached, mentored and transitioned new engineer on front-end technology

Sep 2012 – August 2015 Full-Stack Software Engineer (University Placement) | Serli, France

Extensive research and prototyping for the well-established Java dev shop during study breaks to assist the company in providing high quality client solutions.

- Programmed dependency injection containers in Java binding CDI and OSGi technologies
- Assisted in implementing the TCK of Google App Engine, working with Google and RedHat
- Built a PaaS platform's framework with Node.js on a cluster of Raspberry Pi in INSA Lyon laboratory

Jun 2014 – Aug 2014 Intern | Optimal Workshop, Wellington / New Zealand

Assisted the UX design firm with implementing, developing and analysing user experience regarding a back office subscription with activity visualisation using D3.js. Migrated database to fit the new payment management system and created a Chrome extension to make integration tests easier to set up.

erences Available on Request						